Communist Chinese political movement collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Communist Chinese political movement collection
1928-1980
1951-circa 1980
2014C24
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes (6 linear feet)
Memoirs, investigation records, and judicial testimony and decrees, relating to political dissidence and to prosecutions for political offenses in China.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
The collection contains biographies, memoirs, investigation records, confessions, and judicial testimony and decrees, relating to political dissidence and to prosecutions for political offenses in China from the 1950s to the 1970s, collected from various sources in China. It also features internal party documents from key political campaigns and individual case files and dossiers from the early 1950s to the final years of the Mao era.
Although the collection is called the Communist Chinese Political Movement Collection, the word yundong (movement), which once occupied a prominent place in the political lexicon of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), has become archaic in the twenty-first century. Yet the the various movements launched by the CCP served the purposes of maintaining its political legitimacy and the sense that Chinese society was moving toward a brighter future. With every political movement launched at various stages of its rule after 1949, the CCP experienced significant transformation, along with the landscape of Chinese politics, culture, and society.
Dissenters-China.; Political crimes and offenses-China.
- "Campaign to suppress counterrevvolutionaries," Fuqing county list of suppressed counterrevolutionaries, 1951 (Box 1: 1)
- "Purge of hidden counterrevolutionaries" campaign files, 1950s-1959 (Box 1)
  - Zhang Yaosan case, 1957 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Shen Weichang case, 1950s (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Wu Jian case, 1959 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- "Speak out boldly" campaign, Wang Huapu case, 1957 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- "Three antis" campaign, 1969-1970 (Box 1-2)
  - Case of Ouyang Fu and others, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Fei Zhenyu case, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Wang Shengshan case, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- "One strike, three antis" campaign, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Zhang Jianhua case, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Li Shiping case, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- "Cleansing the class ranks" campaign, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Wang Jinglin case, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Liu Zhiheng case, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- "Four Clean-ups" campaign, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Lu Dianxue file, 1965 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Zang Mianzhi file, 1965, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Chang Junyue case, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Ma Kui case, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 16)
- "Campaign to denounce the Gang of Four," Wu Jixu case, 1977 (Box 3: 17)
- Court files, 1951-5963 (Box 3)
  - Reports on cases concerning rural collectives, 1956 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Li Huawen, Li Benyuan, Lin Senlin embazzlement case, 1951 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Chen Guiying, Ren Weiyu, drug dealing, 1951 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Xiong Meichuan, profiteering and tax evation, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Reports on spring farming sabotage cases, 1956 (Box-folder 3: 22)
- "War on Opium" files, 1952, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Yang Xinzhi case, 1952 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Lin Hanzhang case, 1952 (Box-folder 3: 24)
- Prosecutor's file, criminal record of Mo Yuanchun, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 25)
- Personal history files, undated unless specified (Box 3-4)
  - Gong Mingxun, counterrevolutionary (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Zheng Tao, petit bourgeois, 1953 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Huang keming biography, 1952 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Zheng Zhu'an, landlord (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Leng Guangrong, grafter (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Xie Zhiqing, former KMT soldier and dissident (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Hu Yingpu, policemen under Japanese occupation (Box-folder 4: 32)
- Rehabilitation files, undated (Box-folder 4)
  - Gu Guobin, landlord (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Sun Chunqi, rightist (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Tang Bo, rightist (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Yu Xinle, rightist (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Wang Yazhong, rightist (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Tong Huairang, rightist (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - Zuo Yuanhua, rightist (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - Gao Tingzhang, rightist (Box-folder 4: 40)
- Organizational documents, 1969-1970s (Box 4)
  - Guangdong Dongshan Machinery Repair Factory internal investigation documents, 1970s (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - Public offender registry of Jiangyou region, Feb.1969-Oct.1969 (Box-folder 4: 42)
- Party documents, 1962-1980s, undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous documents from the Cultural Revolution, undated (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Amended collective farm regulation, 1962 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Party decree and random documents from Jiangsu Province during the Cultural Revolution, undated (Box-folder 5: 45)
- Railway station architectual design from the 1980s (Guangzhou, Huangshan, Jianggao. 广州，黄山，江高站) (Box-folder 5: 46)
- Private correspondence of Chen Yong, 1980s (Box-folder 5: 47)
- She Junnan sketch book (佘俊南), undated (Box-folder 5: 48)
- Architectual drawing of a historical building in Panyu, Guangdong from the 1980s (番禺余荫山房及瑜园) (Box-folder 5: 49)
- Veteran certificates, reference letter form, undated (Box-folder 5: 50)
- Incremental Materials 2015 (Box 6-9)
  - Wutai County files, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6: 51-53)
  - Wutai County files "Four Clean Ups" campaign, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 54)
  - Yuncheng people's commune, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 55)
  - Tianhe people's commune, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6: 56-60)
  - Tianhe people's commune, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 61)
  - Tianhe people's commune, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 62)
  - Tianhe people's commune, 1973 (Box-folder 7: 63)
  - Yuanping County people's committee, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 64)
  - Yuanping County people's committee, 1957 (Box-folder 7: 65)
  - Yuanping County people's committee, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 66)
  - Miamyang County revolutionary committee files, undated (Box-folder 7: 67)
  - Changchun Geology College files, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 8: 68)
  - Second Geological Exploration Crew Revolutionary committee files, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 8: 69)
  - Pei County People's Procuratorate files, undated (Box-folder 8: 70)
  - CCP "Big Character Poster" files, undated (Box-folder 8: 71-72)
  - Exposure of Judge Jiang files, undated (Box-folder 8: 73)
  - "Four Clean-ups" Campaign files (Box-folder 9: 74)
  - CCP Party directives (Box-folder 9: 75)
  - Hao Zhenru trial files, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9: 76)
  - Li Pinh case file, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 9: 77)
  - Ansham Public Security Bureau files, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 9: 78)
  - Sha Shi Public Security Bureau, 1957 (Box-folder 9: 79)
  - PLA Central-South Military District files, undated (Box-folder 9: 80)
  - Fu Chaorui cadre file, undated (Box-folder 9: 81)
  - Liu Yongcheng cadre file, undated (Box-folder 9: 82)
  - Xing Baoren cadre file, undated (Box-folder 9: 83)
  - Zhang Wenhua cadre file, undated (Box-folder 9: 84)
  - Cao Libo File, undated (Box-folder 9: 85)
  - Lian Weiqi File, undated (Box-folder 9: 86)
- Incremental Materials 2016
  - Wang Sheng File, 1956 (Box-folder 10: 87)
  - Zhang Zhongxian File, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 10: 88)
  - Tang Yimin File, 1956 (Box-folder 10: 89)
  - Xiao Huanan File, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 10: 90)
  - Sha Caizhang File, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 10: 91)
  - Li Xingzhou File, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 10: 92)
  - Luo Dehua File, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 10: 93)
  - Gong Yiping File, 1959 (Box-folder 11: 94)
  - Wang Tingfang File, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 11: 95)
  - Gao Mancai File, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 96)
  - Zhang Shuming File, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 11: 97)
  - Wang Fazhou File, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 11: 98)
  - Wang Wei File, 1949-1958 (Box-folder 11: 99)
  - Sun Zhenyan File, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 12: 100)
  - Ma Shoutian File, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 12: 101)
  - Liu Hanchen File, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 12: 102)
  - Li Bingyao File, 1959 (Box-folder 12: 103)
  - Jia Xigu File, 1959 (Box-folder 12: 104)
  - Wang Lianyu Case, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 12: 105)
  - Zhao Xizhen File, 1954-1964 (Box-folder 12: 106)
  - Wang Denghai Case, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 12: 107)
  - Fujian Minhou Court Case, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 13: 108)
  - Ma Jinyuan Poison Case, 1971 (Box-folder 13: 109)
  - Tianhe Socialist Education Work Team Materials, 1965 (Box-folder 13: 110)
  - Dukoubao Village Commune Xipingshan Team Village History, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 13: 111)
  - Ma Zhenliang and Bai Maosheng files, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 112)
  - Dukoubao Village Commune Xipingshan Team Education Record, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 113)
  - Huang Jianguo File, 1960s (Box-folder 14: 114)
  - Various cadre files, 1979 (Box-folder 14: 115)
  - Personnel Files, 1950s and 1960s (Box-folder 14: 116)
  - Employee Introduction Letters, 1952- (Box-folder 14: 117)
  - Infrastructure and Organization Department Files, 1953 (Box-folder 14: 118)
  - Salary and grain distribution roster, 1954 (Box-folder 14: 119)
  - Government documents on infrastructure building, 1955 (Box-folder 14: 120)
  - Infrastructure building plan, 1953 (Box-folder 14: 121)
  - Procution and Finance Plan, 1963 (Box-folder 14: 122)
  - Admin Files, 1953 (Box-folder 15: 123)
  - Ju Naihong files, 1970 (Box-folder 15: 124)
  - Chengdu Geological Exploration Institute Revolutionary Committee Files, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 15: 125)
  - Land titles, 1951 (Box-folder 15: 126)
  - Obituary, 1928 (Box-folder 15: 127)
  - Ji-Lu-Ru Government Proclamation, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 128)
  - Divorce papers, 1970s (Box-folder 15: 129)
  - Soldier diary, 1977 (Box-folder 15: 130)
  - Personal Diary, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 15: 131)
  - Personal Diary, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 15: 132)
  - Liu Zehui expulsion from the Party, Zhiguoshi Party Committee, Lingxi Communex, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 133)
  - Liang Zhenhai expulsion from the Party, Zhiguoshi Party Committee, Lingxi Commune, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 134)
  - Li Fenggang economic irregularities, deputy production team leader, Shuiyu Production Brigade, Lingxi Commune, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 135)
  - Zhao Dongyin rehabilitation, Lingxi Commune, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 136)
  - Lingxi Commune, Party member roster, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 137)
  - Lingxi Commune, list of "five elements"; obiturary for revolutionary martyrs (Box-folder 16: 138)
  - "Four Clean-ups" Campaign: Ge Luojun case, Haoshanzhuang Brigade, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 139)
  - "Four Clean-ups" Campaign: Ge Luoyu case, Haoshanzhuang Brigade, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 140)
  - "Four Clean-ups" Campaign: Ge Yuqin case, Haoshanzhuang Brigade, Yi County, Hebei Province (Box-folder 16: 141)
  - Statistical registry for "controlled elements", Shandong Province, files 1-4 (Box-folder 16: 142-145)
  - Personal Files (Box-folder 16: 146-147)